I sit across from
people all day, every day who feel like
there's something wrong with them
because they don't have a partner.
We get Fed stories through pop culture
that are just the prologue to love, right?
it's just finding someone.
So many people sit across from me
and say they've never been
in a long term relationship.
And yet when I dig a little deeper,
of course, they have these lifelong
friendships or mentorships or coaching
relationships that are just as valuable
and just as important.
But there's no representation.
When I was in my 20s
and I went into therapy
for the first time,
I had all of these feelings
from my therapist.
And I was also in grad school
to be a therapist
and had never really heard of this.
And so I was thinking about her
all the time, and I felt
a little bit obsessed.
And then I felt really ashamed.
And maybe 10 years ago,
I started to go on Reddit.
And every day there's like five,
six, seven posts
about people who are horrified
and mortified that they have
so many feelings for this person
that they're paying to talk to.
So I got really curious about that
and what I realized is that
part of what creates shame around
having these intense feelings
is that we don't have
a frame of reference.
So that's what led me to think of the term
platonic intimacy and to start
looking at other relationships.
The younger people
are so much more open to
what I think are the exciting new ways
we're looking at relationships.
I think that younger people
today are have more hope
than any other generation in my lifetime
that I've been in relationship to.
And we have an opportunity
to teach them that there are
so many kinds of love in the world
instead of having them
go down the same path of looking for that
one person, which is also great,
but not the only option.
I'm doing great, I'm a relational trauma
therapist in Vancouver.
Welcome to 10X as you.