True reconciliation
in Canada really is about learning.
And let's be transparent,
let's be honest, a lot of the history
that we are exposed to within
this country is kind of hided.
I think that as Canadian citizens,
we've all heard the R word reconciliation,
but never do we ever really have the time
or the opportunity
to unpack what that really mean.
A pivotal moment in my life
was delivering a presentation on culture
safety, in humility and talking
about the atrocities of our past.
To a group of professionals.
And at the very end of that presentation,
one of the participants
had raised their hand
and wanted to offer a comment.
And she said, I am a newcomer to Canada.
And when I arrived in this country,
I was fleeing, you know, oppression
in my own home country.
And when I arrived here, you know,
I didn't know anything
about indigenous people.
And I still don't know very much.
But this conversation
has transformed forever, the way I look
at indigenous relations in this country.
That was changing
and defining moment in my life
and in my career
on just how important these conversations
are that we as Canadians
and we as human beings feel much better
when we know what I've learned over
the years of talking about reconciliation
for a living has equipped me
with a knowledge
and a profound understanding
that this work really
is about relationship building,
about learning about one another.
In that aha moment that I had,
I thought of no place else
better than the prestigious
platform of a TED.
Talk to share this knowledge
and share this information.
Hi, my name is Limpia.
I am Cosulich from CTSI First Nation.
And welcome to Ted ZAPU.